Hello, this is JB.
I am with the Austin Homebrew Supply in Austin, Texas.
Today we are discussing beer making equipment and wine making equipment.
We're going to talk about thermometers right now, which is more applicable to beer than wine, although some people will take, use high, use a thermometer for wine making.
It's generally more applicable to beer making.
But, none-the-less, we sell a different, a few different varieties of thermometers.
I'll just show you three different varieties here to start out with.
Our standard on is a floating thermometer.
It's going to come with our deluxe beer equipment kits.
And these guys simply, you just drop them in to whatever liquid you're trying to get the temperature of.
Generally, in beer making there's two stages that you'll take these readings.
One of which is when you're steeping the grain at the first part of the, of the brewing process.
You need to make sure that you achieve particular temperatures.
This will help you to make sure that you're not too hot or too cool.
There's one other stage that you want to use this at.
It's right before you pitch the yeast in to it.
You've got to make sure that your beer is not too hot.
If you put the living yeast in to too hot of an environment it'll kill the yeast.
So, thermometer's come in handy for beer making.
Comes in a fahrenheit and centigrade scale.
Most folks in America talk fahrenheit.
So, this is our floating thermometer, our basic one.
It's about a seven dollar thermometer.
We also have one that's a very fast reader.
We call it the lab thermometer.
It doesn't float, but it reads real quickly, so you immerse it in to the liquid and get a reading with in maybe fifteen seconds or so.
And then the lastly we have our dial type thermometer, which has a little clip on the side of it.
You could put it on the side of a kettle and monitor the temperature inside of the either wort, or when you're actually taking your temperature right before you pitch the yeast.
So, a few different types of thermometer's that you can use in brewing.